<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Dagon's fall, or, The knight turn'd out of commission</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1680</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A35731</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing D111</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R7739</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13240307</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 13240307</idno>
            <idno type="VID">98624</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A35731)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 98624)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 451:11)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Dagon's fall, or, The knight turn'd out of commission</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1680]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Waller, William, --  Sir, d. 1699.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1660-1688 --  Sources.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  London --  17th century</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:98624:1"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:98624:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>DAGON's Fall: Or the KNIGHT Turn'd out of COMMISSION.</head>
            <l>GOod God! what means this ſudden Alteration!</l>
            <l>The Fop that has ſo long diſturb'd the Nation,</l>
            <l>By's Pride, and Pomp, and Pow'r, is now <hi>Turn'd out,</hi>
            </l>
            <l>And hardly pity'd by the ſilly Rout.</l>
            <l>He was as Stout, and lofty as old <hi>Hector,</hi>
            </l>
            <l>Uſurp'd the Power of our damn'd Protector;</l>
            <l>As fierce and Cruel as a Tyger's whelp,</l>
            <l>He wanted neither ſtrength, nor art, nor help</l>
            <l>To do and undo; he was grown ſo great,</l>
            <l>That the Creation was amaz'd to ſee't.</l>
            <l>He had his Coach and Horſes, Footmen too,</l>
            <l>And into th' City rode, to make a ſhew;</l>
            <l>But little thought when drawn by <hi>W</hi>—</l>
            <l>His fatal downfal it had been ſo near.</l>
            <l>To put a Sword into a Madmans hand,</l>
            <l>It may make Bloody work within the Land.</l>
            <l>Papiſts and Proteſtants were all alike,</l>
            <l>Both ſent to lodge with <hi>Church</hi> and thin-jaw'd <hi>Dyke.</hi>
            </l>
            <l>No Day ſcarce paſs'd without ſome miſchief done,</l>
            <l>Into all Companies the Fool did run.</l>
            <l>The Goaler ſure gave him a ſnack of Fees,</l>
            <l>For Priſoners flock'd ev'n like a Swarm of Bees.</l>
            <l>Here ten were ſent him for a Popiſh Plot,</l>
            <l>There two more for to pleaſe a Buggering Sot.</l>
            <l>Then a new Plot is feign'd, and more ſecur'd,</l>
            <l>'Uds fleſh, my Friends, this cannot be endur'd!</l>
            <l>Printers, Apprentices, and many more,</l>
            <l>In all I do believe near twice two ſcore.</l>
            <l>They are all Plotters, yet by <hi>Jove</hi> not one,</l>
            <l>Can tell you what was ſaid, or what was done.</l>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:98624:2"/>
            <l>The <hi>Gatehouſe</hi> is become a <hi>Babel</hi> now,</l>
            <l>Confuſions came upon us none knew how.</l>
            <l>But he that wrought the miſchief now is found,</l>
            <l>'Twill puzzle any man to prove him ſound.</l>
            <l>He's rotten at the heart i'le lay my life,</l>
            <l>No wonder he begot us all this ſtrife.</l>
            <l>Well, now the cauſe is gone, the effect will ceaſe,</l>
            <l>I hope we ſhall enjoy our former peace.</l>
            <l>This little Leaven leaven'd the whole lump,</l>
            <l>And made us fear another ſawcy <hi>Rump.</hi>
            </l>
            <l>He ſtudy'd out new Plots, and for what ends?</l>
            <l>Only to pleaſe his <hi>Prerbyterian</hi> friends.</l>
            <l>Ah but my Friend, thou thy laſt Dice haſt thrown,</l>
            <l>For which the <hi>Presbyters</hi> begin to groan,</l>
            <l>Thy buſie active Soul (I do not jeſt)</l>
            <l>Had lately ſent it a <hi>Quietus eſt.</hi>
            </l>
            <l>And that which doth thy grief and ſorrow double,</l>
            <l>Thou art not Rich for all thy needleſs trouble.</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Soul take thine eaſe,</hi> thou very well mai'ſt ſing,</l>
            <l>For thou haſt got a Writ of eaſe from th' King:</l>
            <l>
               <hi>Thou haſt much Goods laid up for many years,</hi>
            </l>
            <l>Sing that and I will give thee both my Ears.</l>
            <l>Leave but the Factious out, go through the City,</l>
            <l>Thou wilt not find a Man enclin'd to pity.</l>
            <l>Hang him cries one, he was a buſie <hi>Knave,</hi>
            </l>
            <l>He ſhe'wd no mercy, nor he none ſhall have.</l>
            <l>Miſchief was all his aim, and his deſign,</l>
            <l>When he brought <hi>Hickey</hi> to a glaſs of Wine.</l>
            <l>The miſchief which ſoeagerly he ſought</l>
            <l>For others, he himſelf too dearly bought:</l>
            <l>But I am almoſt weary of my Rhimes,</l>
            <l>For I conſider theſe are Trayterous times.</l>
            <l>Had but this buſie Fool his late Commiſſion,</l>
            <l>This would have coſt me a devout Submiſſion;</l>
            <l>I had been ſurely ſent to Goal for Treaſon</l>
            <l>As <hi>Thompſon</hi> was, and had a greater reaſon:</l>
            <l>But God be thanked curſt-Cows have ſhort Horns,</l>
            <l>He muſt and ſhall endure our Flouts and Scorns.</l>
            <l>We may go boldly on, and fear no fall;</l>
            <l>No painted Staff will anſwer at his call.</l>
            <l>Now he is down, down with him, now 's the Seaſon;</l>
            <l>For if he riſe he'l Goal us all for <hi>TREASON.</hi>
            </l>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
